[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [2, 3, 5, 4], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to b2?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 0}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+N\u2082+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081+N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "+N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+N\u2082+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081+N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to b1?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to B?", "options": ["N3 perpendicular up", "N3 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 0}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, N3, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 50cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 50sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082-N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082-N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "+N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["N\u2081: Normal between red block and Big blockyellow block and red blockyellow block and Big block", "N\u2081: Normal between ", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082-N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082-N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, N3, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 50cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 50sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": []}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= -21.13, a\u2082= 7.07, N\u2081= -35.21, N\u2083= 7.07", "a\u2081= 7.07, a\u2082= -21.13, N\u2081= -35.21, N\u2083= 7.07", "a\u2081= 7.07, a\u2082= -21.13, N\u2081= 7.07, N\u2083= -35.21", "a\u2081= -7.07, a\u2082= -7.07, N\u2081= 21.13, N\u2083= 35.21"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= -7.07, a\u2082= -7.07, N\u2081= 21.13, N\u2083= 35.21"]}]}]